Guide to the Ithaca City Federation of Women's Organizations records, 1910-1972.
Ithaca City Federation of Women's Organizations records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca City Federation of Women's Organizations records, 1910-1972.
2643
Ithaca City Federation of Women's Organizations.
4.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Manuscripts, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes correspondence, preliminary sketches, and blueprints concerning the construction of the Women's Community Building in Ithaca, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes correspondence, preliminary sketches, and blueprints concerning the construction of the Women's Community Building in Ithaca, New York (1950s); general and committee correspondence; correspondence and survey materials pertaining to a proposed Ithaca War Memorial (1949); histories of the Federation; Constitution and bylaws; reports; minutes; financial reports; scrapbooks and yearbooks; clippings; program booklets; and other materials.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ithaca City Federation of Women's Organizations.
Subjects:
Community organizations.; War memorials--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Women--Societies and clubs.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Architectural drawings.; Blueprints.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access restricted to permission of the donor.
CONTAINER LIST
- Administrative Files, 1912-1969
  - City Federation of Women's Organizations (CFWO) photocopy of office record of incorporation, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CFWO histories, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Building Fund Drive, 1921-1922, 1924, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1949-1950, 1952-1953, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ballots, 1952, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CFWO general business, reports and miscellaneous, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New Building Committee, reports, minutes and drafts, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New Building Committee miscellaneous, 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Women's Community Building Memorial, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Report of the survey for the building and expansion of the Women's Community Building, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Agda Osborn,War Memorial Committee notes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Agda Osborn, reports, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Agda Osborn notebooks, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agda Osborn, New Building Campaign, 1950, 1951, 1956-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Agda Osborn, New Building Campaign, 1959-11-1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Agda Osborn, New Building Campaign correspondence and budgets, etc., 1950, 1955, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Agda Osborn, New Building Campaign correspondence and business, 1950, 1952-1953, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Agda Osborn, New Building Campaign member organization correspondence and business, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Agda Osborn, other organizations, 1950, 1954, 1956, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Agda Osborn, correspondence and drafts, miscellaneous notes, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Walter H. Foertsch correspondence, 1957-1958, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Robert A. Ives property and Baker property, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Agda Osborn notebooks, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Agda Osborn, correspondence and drafts, miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Pledges, etc., Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Undated fragments, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Excerpts from survey returns, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - War Memorial correspondence, 1945, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - War Memorial news clippings, 1945, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Surveys made by War Memorial Committee, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Hearings before War Memorial Committee, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - War Memorial Suggestions by individuals, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - War Dead List, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Compilations of surveys, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - War Memorial miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - War Memorial Survey organizational responses, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10-14)
  - War Memorial Survey M.I.A. response, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - War Memorial Survey newspaper questionnaire, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - War Memorial Survey, individual responses, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Survey responses, Undated (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
  - War Memorial Survey responses, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1-12)
  - Special records of the CFWO, 1875, 1957-1959, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    History, Sept. 26, 1957, Mrs. H.S. Osborn; History, May 22, 1965, A.S. Osborn; 1959 letter to Club Presidents; 1968 Constitution and bylaws; Brochure of proposed building 1958-1959; Report of survey for new building; program booklets; Letter-head, first Federation Community Building; Description of Brooks Mansion, 1875
  - Ithaca Daily News, taken over for the day by women, 1912-05-24 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CFWO Constitution and By-laws, drafts and copies, and Board of Directors committees, 1915, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - CFWO miscellaneous correspondence (found in 1910-1916 record book), 1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Purchase of building; First community rest room; W.F. Willcox speech; Opening of Women's Community Building
  - Complete file of annual program booklets, 1930-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - 150 year anniversary, City Federation history, by Agda Osborn, 1965-05-22 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Supplement, Women's Clubs, 1966-11-11 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - CFWO minutes, 1930-1931, 1936-1937, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1920-06-1921-12 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - CFWO minutes, 1921-01-1922-12 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - CFWO minutes, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - CFWO minutes, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors and CFWO minutes, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1933-09-1935 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - CFWO minutes, 1933-11-1935 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1936-1937-03 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - CFWO minutes, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - CFWO minutes, 1938-10-1939 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - CFWO minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - CFWO minutes and finance reports, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CFWO and Executive Board Roll, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CFWO and Executive Committee minutes, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - CFWO minutes and Membership lists, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Loose papers in Board minutes, 1945-1958 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - CFWO recording secretary reports, 1945-05-1946-03 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Executive secretary's reports, 1945-12-1946 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Recording secretary's reports, 1946-05-1947-03 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Executive secretary's reports, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - CFWO recording secretary minutes, 1947-05-1948-03 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - CFWO recording secretary minutes, 1948-05-1949-03 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Executive secretary's reports, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ithaca Federation of Women's Organizations reports and minutes, 1950-1952 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - CFWO correspondence and reports, 1950-1956 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - CFWO minutes and reports, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Building and Expansion Committee, 1955-09-1956-10 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - All committee minutes, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - CFWO minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Executive secretary's report, 1957-04-1959-10 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Business records and reports, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Business records and reports, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Business records and reports, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Business records and reports, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Business records and reports, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - CFWO, Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Business records and reports, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Business records and reports, 1966, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of CFWO luncheon, 1965-09 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Record book of meeting minutes, 1910-01-08-1918-03-08 (Box 8)
  - Record book of meeting minutes, 1916-04-1917 (Box 8)
  - Record book of meeting minutes, 1937-1945 (Box 8)
  - Record book of meeting minutes, 1945-1958 (Box 8)
  - Record book of Board of Directors and Executive Board minutes, 1959-01-1960-12 (Box 8)
  - Blueprints and sketches of proposed Women's Community Building, Undated (Box Map-case, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks and Histories, 1910-1972
  - Early CFWO papers, 1920-1922, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A History of the City Federation of Women's Organizations of Ithaca, NY 1910-1969 and the Women's Community Building, 1910-1969 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook of CFWO publicity, 1965-1972 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook of clippings of CFWO, collected by Elizabeth Senft, Program Director, 1927-1942 (Box 8)
  - CFWO scrapbook, 1920-1924 (Box 9)
  - CFWO scrapbook, 1934-1942 (Box 9)
  - CFWO scrapbook, 1942-1950 (Box 9)
  - CFWO scrapbook, 1950-1953 (Box 9)
  - Record book of clippings from the Ithaca Journal, 1956-1961 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook of CFWO publicity, 1961-1965 (Box 9)